In a town like Twin Peaks, no one is innocent.
Twin Peaks: Fire Walk with Me is a drama, mystery,
horror film directed by David Lynch.
In the questionable town of Deer Meadow, Washington, FBI Agent Desmond
inexplicably disappears while hunting for the man who murdered a teen girl.
The killer is never apprehended, and, after experiencing dark visions and supernatural encounters,
Agent Dale Cooper chillingly predicts that the culprit will claim another life.
Meanwhile, in the more cozy town of Twin Peaks, hedonistic beauty Laura
Palmer hangs with lowlifes and seems destined for a grisly fate.
Laura Palmer, played by Sheryl Lee.
Leland Palmer, played by Ray Wise.
Shelly Johnson, played by Mädchen Amick.
Bobby Briggs, played by Dana Ashbrook.
Ronette Pulaski, played by Phoebe Augustine.
Phillip Jeffries, played by David Bowie.
Twin Peaks: Fire Walk with Me is a 1992 psychological horror film directed
by David Lynch, and co-written by Lynch and Robert Engels.
It serves as a prequel to seasons one and two of the television series Twin
Peaks (1990–1991), created and produced by Mark Frost and Lynch.
It begins with the FBI's investigation into the murder of Teresa Banks (Pamela Gidley) before shifting to the last seven days of the life
of Laura Palmer (Sheryl Lee), a popular-but-troubled high school student in the fictional town of Twin Peaks, Washington.
Palmer's murder was the primary plot thread of the original TV series.
Greenlit shortly after the TV series was cancelled, Fire Walk with Me has a much darker tone than the TV series
and does not address many of season two's unfinished narratives, including its cliffhanger ending.
Although most of the television cast reprised their roles for the film, many
comparatively lighthearted scenes featuring town residents were cut.
In addition, the series' main star, Kyle MacLachlan (Dale Cooper), asked for his role to be
downsized, and Lara Flynn Boyle's character Donna Hayward was recast with Moira Kelly.
In 2014, several deleted scenes were recut and
released as Twin Peaks: The Missing Pieces.
Fire Walk with Me premiered at the 1992 Cannes Film
Festival in competition for the Palme d'Or.
The film was notoriously polarizing: Lynch said that the film was booed at
Cannes, and the American press generally panned the film.
The film was controversial for its frank and vivid depiction of sexual abuse, its
relative absence of fan-favorite characters, and its surrealistic style.
It was a box-office bomb in North America, but fared better in Japan and France.
Due to the poor reception, plans for a sequel were abandoned.
The film has been positively re-evaluated in the 21st century, and is
now widely regarded as one of Lynch's major works.
Lynch and Frost eventually received funding to produce a third season of the TV
series in 2017, which revisited several plot threads from the film.
In 2019, the British Film Institute ranked Fire Walk
with Me the fourth-best film of the 1990s.
The film explores themes of high school, small town,
double life, sexual abuse, detective.
The tone is dark and emotional and mind_bending.